<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Server Management on think twice code once!</title>
    <link>http://iocast.github.io/categories/server-management/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Server Management on think twice code once!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved © 2017</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://iocast.github.io/categories/server-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining a Active Directory on Linux - the easiest way!</title>
      <link>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/linux-join-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/linux-join-ad/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way, at least for me, is to use the &lt;code&gt;likewise-open&lt;/code&gt; package. You can find the official documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/LikewiseOpen&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Under Ubuntu you can simple install this package using &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;apt-get install likewise-open
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have installed it, you can join a Active Directory (AD) as follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;domainjoin-cli join --ou Hosting/&amp;lt;path&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;to&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;your&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;organization-unit&amp;gt; &amp;lt;server&amp;gt; &amp;lt;login-user&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where you need to define the path to your organization unit, which is displayed in the AD as a folder. The second parameter is the server and the last parameter is the user, that have rights to add new things in the AD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without any configuration, all AD users have login rights to your server. At first login, each user is getting a personal user folder under &lt;code&gt;/home/likewise-open&lt;/code&gt; and then a subfolder named as his username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;restricting-access-to-specific-groups&#34;&gt;Restricting access to specific groups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, LikewiseOpen allows all AD users to logon. To limit this to specific groups you need to add required membership settings as follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;lwconfig RequireMembershipOf &amp;quot;&amp;lt;server&amp;gt;\\&amp;lt;group-1&amp;gt;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;erver&amp;gt;\\&amp;lt;group-2&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
lw-update-dns
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you forget which groups have access to you server, you could check it by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;lwconfig --detail RequireMembershipOf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;login&#34;&gt;Login&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you are able to login to your server using active directory authentication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;ssh &amp;lt;ad_domain&amp;gt;\\&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;server&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac OS X file server migration</title>
      <link>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/osx-file-server-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/osx-file-server-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing a OS X server is sometimes a pain, when it comes to manage ACL permissions on the file system using OS X Server share point application. For example if you want to migrate from one file server to another you need to define all shares and ACLs again or if you want to propagate permissions on a share with explicit ACLs on a sub-directory you are going to overwrite these explicit ACLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to solve these problems and many more I created a little bash script which is able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sync files from a remote server using &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;changing the POSIX permissions on the local server after sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating optionally a share point for each folder to be synced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propagating ACLs on a share point or on a individual directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these feature can be used independently. For more information see the project description: &lt;a href=&#34;http://iocast.github.io/projects/file-server-management.html&#34;&gt;server migration tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>