<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Likewise Open on think twice code once!</title>
    <link>http://iocast.github.io/tags/likewise-open/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Likewise Open on think twice code once!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved © 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://iocast.github.io/tags/likewise-open/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining a Active Directory on Linux - the easiest way!</title>
      <link>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/linux-join-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://iocast.github.io/post/server-management/linux-join-ad/</guid>
      <description>

<p>The easiest way, at least for me, is to use the <code>likewise-open</code> package. You can find the official documentation <a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/LikewiseOpen">here</a>. Under Ubuntu you can simple install this package using <code>apt-get</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">apt-get install likewise-open
</code></pre>

<p>Once you have installed it, you can join a Active Directory (AD) as follow.</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">domainjoin-cli join --ou Hosting/&lt;path&gt;/&lt;to&gt;/&lt;your&gt;/&lt;organization-unit&gt; &lt;server&gt; &lt;login-user&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>where you need to define the path to your organization unit, which is displayed in the AD as a folder. The second parameter is the server and the last parameter is the user, that have rights to add new things in the AD.</p>

<p>Without any configuration, all AD users have login rights to your server. At first login, each user is getting a personal user folder under <code>/home/likewise-open</code> and then a subfolder named as his username.</p>

<h2 id="restricting-access-to-specific-groups">Restricting access to specific groups</h2>

<p>By default, LikewiseOpen allows all AD users to logon. To limit this to specific groups you need to add required membership settings as follow:</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">lwconfig RequireMembershipOf &quot;&lt;server&gt;\\&lt;group-1&gt;&quot; &quot;&lt;erver&gt;\\&lt;group-2&gt;&quot;
lw-update-dns
</code></pre>

<p>If you forget which groups have access to you server, you could check it by running the following command:</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">lwconfig --detail RequireMembershipOf
</code></pre>

<h2 id="login">Login</h2>

<p>Now you are able to login to your server using active directory authentication:</p>

<pre><code class="language-bash">ssh &lt;ad_domain&gt;\\&lt;user&gt;@&lt;server&gt;
</code></pre>
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>